A Finding Aid to the Paul Vanderbilt Papers, 1854-1992, bulk 1945-1992, in the Archives of American Art AAA.vandpaul
Archives of American Art
- Diaries, 1926-1990; Series 5; 0.5 Linear feet Box 8
  - Diaries, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Reference Files, 1877-1992; Series 6; 2.5 Linear feet Boxes 8-10, 26
  This series consists primarily of printed materials collected by Vanderbilt on numerous topics of interest.
  - Abstractions in Commercial Advertising, 1970s (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Absurd, 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Aging, 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Allen, Mary North, circa 1986 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Americana, 1952-1979 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - American Friends Service Committee, 1971-1973 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Archeology, 1883 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Archival Organization, 1954-1979 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Art, 1949-1990 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Art Education, 1970-1974 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Art Historians, Individual, 1920s (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Bibliographical Lists, 1937-1952 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Books, 1954-1991 (Box 8, Folder 24-25)
  - Book Statements, Support, circa 1950-1990 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Calligraphy, circa 1950s (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Cartoons, 1971-1987 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Catalogs for Visual Resources, 1973-1979 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Catalogs for Visual Resources, 1973-1979 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Charlesworth, Sarah, 1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Children's Museums, 1930s (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - City Periphery, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, Movie Review & Reading, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Oversized material housed in Box 26.
  - Collage, 1984-1987 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Collage, Materials, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Confirmations, 1969-1979 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Constructive Ideas, Organization, 1931-1947 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Copyright, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Culture Comment, 1963-1992 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Death, 1965-1973 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Education, 1960-1988 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Education, Alternative, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Energy, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Faces, 1930s-1940s (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Far Out, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Favorite Causes, 1964-1985 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Feminism and Women's Liberation, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Filmmaking, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Foreign Libraries, British Museum in London, 1930s (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Foreign Libraries, Germany, 1930s (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Foreign Libraries, National Central Library in London, 1933-1937 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Foreign Libraries, Royal Institute of British Architects Library in London, 1930s (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Future Predictions, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Good Ideas, 1977-1990 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Graphics, 1968-1992 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Happenings, 1967-1979 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Harvard, 1968-1986 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - History, 1965-1979 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Holography, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - How "Man" Room, 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Illustration of Book Review Examples, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Images of Cars, 1948-1952 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Images of Figures Off Balance, circa 1980 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Individual Artists, 1964-1980 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Interesting Faces, 1980s (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - International Center of Photography, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Johns Hopkins University Press Catalog, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Kusnerz, Peggy Ann, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Law, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Lettering and Calligraphy, 1977-1987 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Liquor, 1980s (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Literature, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Madison, Wisconsin, 1986-1991 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Maps, 1980s (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Medicine, 1966-1974 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Microfiche, circa 1974 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Microphotography, 1934-1954 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Microphotography, Charles E. Rush in Europe, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Miscellaneous Quotations for Use in Writing, 1950s-1960s (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Motion Pictures, 1954-1977 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Multiple Images, 1971-1991 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Mysteries and Symbolism, 1970-1984 (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Natural Resources, circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Negative, 1960s-1970s (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Neutral, circa 1960s (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Next Layout, 1991-1992 (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - New York City, 1976-1977 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Notable Pictures, 1987-1991 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Old Letterheads, 1880s-1980s (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Overpainting, 1981-1991 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Peace, 1985-1991 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Philosophy, 1968-1977 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Photographs, Auction Prices, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - "Photographic" Writing, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - Piaget, Jean, 1969-1980 (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - Picture Reservoir, Foliage Dense with Form, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Picture Reservoir, Foliage Openings-Light Effects, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - Picture Reservoir, Letter Forms, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - Picture Reservoir, Roads-Surfaces, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - Picture Reservoir, Shoes, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - Picture Reservoir, Suspension-Flight-Movement, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - Picture Reservoir, Transparency-Glass, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - Picture Reservoir, Transparency-Pale Landscapes, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - Picture Reservoir, Transparency-Sky-Air, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 9, Folder 76)
  - Picture Reservoir, Vertical-Linear, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 9, Folder 77)
  - Picture Reservoir, Weight, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - Positive, 1960s-1970s (Box 9, Folder 79)
  - Post Cards, 1910s (Box 9, Folder 80)
  - Post Card Collecting, 1953-1955 (Box 9, Folder 81)
  - Psychology, Perception, 1877-1980 (Box 9, Folder 82)
  - Reporting Sample, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 83)
  - Shocking, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 84)
  - Social, 1972-1980 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Sound Equipment, 1965-1992 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Sources-Ideas, 1930-1947 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - The Sources of Modern Photography Brochure, 1980s (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Storytelling, 1981-1987 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Tableware, 1970s-1980s (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Technology and Economics, 1973-1989 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Trees, 1968-1973 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - United States, 1972-1982 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Various Printed Material, 1863-1991 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Verde Valley School, 1949-1953 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Video, 1985-1988 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Vintage Clothing, circa 1984 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Warburg Institute Library, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - World Situation, circa 1990 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Oversized Material, Picture Reservoir and Clippings for Reading (Box 26)
- Project Files, 1935-1990; Series 7; 3 Linear feet Boxes 10-13
  Project files are comprised of correspondence, notes, and drafts for some of Vanderbilt's major professional projects. Projects with extensive files include an unpublished guide to the iconography of Iran and the Union Library Catalog of Philadelphia. Records regarding the transfer and reclassification of photographs from the FSA to the Library of Congress are found under Vanderbilt's devised title "Stryker Project". There are files relating to his work on thematic panels wherein Vanderbilt combined pairs of photographs with poetry to express a theme. Also in this series are two sound recordings of Jane Rupert and four sound recordings of Vanderbilt discussing his thematic panels.
  The folders for the guide to the iconography of Iran are grouped according to Vanderbilt's original arrangement causing some folder titles to be repetitive.
  - Bibliographic Planning Committee of Philadelphia, circa 1939 (Box 10, Folder 16-18)
  - Guide to the Iconography of Iran (Box 10)
    - General, 1949-1952 (Box 10, Folder 19-20)
    - Bibliography, circa 1950s (Box 10, Folder 21-27)
    - Correspondence, 1951-1952 (Box 10, Folder 28-29)
  - Guide to the Iconography of Iran (Box 11)
    - Facts to Check or Insert, circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Full List-Collections, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Henry Field, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Library of Congress Cards, circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Lists-Keep Checking, 1951-1952 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Motion Pictures, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Motion Pictures Dealing with Iran Draft, 1951-1952 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Motion Pictures Preliminary List, circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - No Attention Required, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Notes, circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 10-12)
    - Ready to Type Drafts, circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Sample Descriptions and Lists, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - "See AF" (Air Force), circa 1952 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - To Write Up, 1951-1952 (Box 11, Folder 16-17)
    - Unfinished Leads, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Writings, circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Acknowledgments, circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Bibliographies, 1951-1952 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Iconographic Applications, circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Methods Used, 1951-1952 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Motion Pictures, Done, circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Organization of the Field, 1951-1952 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Scope, circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Summary, circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - General Guides, circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Introduction, circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Oil and Other Activities, circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Portraits, circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Promotional, circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Surveys, circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Travel Books, circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Welfare, 1950s (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Periodicals, circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 36-37)
    - Commercial Agencies, circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Engineering, circa 1952 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Exhibitions, Filmstrips, Etc., 1951-1952 (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Introduction, circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Modern Painting, circa 1952 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Organize, 1951-1952 (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Posters, Postage Stamps, Etc., circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Public Relations, circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - Private Collections, circa 1952 (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - Sources in Iran, circa 1952 (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - Soviet Resources, circa 1952 (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - Revolution, circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 49)
    - Art-Historic as Iconography, 1951-1952 (Box 11, Folder 50)
  - Guide to the Iconography of Iran (Box 12)
    - European Artists in Iran, circa 1950s (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Modern Popular Art and Westernization, circa 1952 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Native of Material, circa 1950s (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Organization of the Field-Historic Studies, circa 1950s (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Photography, 1951-1952 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Travel Books, circa 1950s (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - 19th Century Art, circa 1950s (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - East-West Relation, circa 1950s (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Ethnology, circa 1950s (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - General Travel, circa 1950s (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Introduction, circa 1950s (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Iranians in Europe, circa 1950s (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Periodicals, circa 1950s (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Historic Materials, circa 1952 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Introduction-Sources, circa 1952 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Private Collections, circa 1952 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Art-Organization, circa 1951 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Files-Private, circa 1950s (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Joseph Seagram Courthouses, 1975-1981 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Material for Noah's Ark, Proposed Book, 1979-1990 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Pairs, Notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Pairings, Photo Associations Tests, undated (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Pairings, Photocopies of Roadside Images, undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Pairings, Promotion, 1981-1989 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Photo Project with Walter McQuade and John Szarkowski, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Materials Regarding Roy Stryker, circa 1950-1964 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Stryker Project, Memos and Photographer Instructions, 1935-1940s (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Stryker Project, Paul Vanderbilt's Activities, 1940s-1950 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Stryker Project, Paul Vanderbilt's Activities, Reports and Notes, 1942-1948 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Stryker Project, Photographs of Workroom, circa 1944-1946 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Stryker Project, Rough Notes by Paul Vanderbilt, circa 1940s (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Stryker, Standard Oil, 1940-1944 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Thematic Panels, General, circa 1984 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Thematic Panels, Discussion with Jane Rupert, 1983; 2 Sound cassettes (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Thematic Panels, Exhibition at Madison Art Center (1987-1988) (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Thematic Panels, Grant, 1983-1986 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Thematic Panels, Index Notes, 1955-1984 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Thematic Panels, Lecture Notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Thematic Panels, Paul Vanderbilt Discussing the Project, 1983; 1 Sound cassettes; 2 sound tape reels (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Thematic Panels, Text of Audio Written and Read by Paul Vanderbilt, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Thematic Panels, Transcript of Analysis, undated (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Thematic Panels Samples, Philosophical Orientation, circa 1970s (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Paul Vanderbilt, Book of Panels, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Union Library Catalog of Philadelphia, 1937-1939 (Box 12, Folder 44-45)
  - Union Library Catalog of Philadelphia, Publications, 1936-1937 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - "Visual Exploration of Paul's Photos and Images," Video Project, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Professional Files, 1854-1991; Series 8; 11.7 Linear feet Boxes 13-24
  This series contains 4 subseries.
  8.1: Library of Congress, 1924-1966
  8.2: Graphic History Society, 1945-1976
  8.3: State Historical Society of Wisconsin, 1854-1989
  8.4: Other Professional Activities, 1927-1991
  This series consists of administrative files, correspondence, printed material, research material, and writings more generally associated with his professional jobs and consulting, arranged by place of employment or organization. Files for the Library of Congress include material on cartoons, classification, a guide to special collections, iconography, photography, and the "Forgotten Photographers" exhibition. The Graphic History Society files include material on bibliographies of iconographic books and the society's publication, Eye to Eye. Found in the State Historical Society of Wisconsin files are materials for the "Photographs as Cultural Resources" conference and for exhibitions of photographs by Vanderbilt. The Farm Security Administration files contain copies of Roy Stryker's correspondence, memoranda, and gossip sheets, and copies of other internal memoranda. Files for the Philadelphia Museum of Art include material on a lantern slide project and a union catalog of art books. Other professional files include Vanderbilt's work as a consultant for several organizations, lecture and workshop documents, as well as files documenting his work with the American Association for State and Local History and as an artist-in-residence at Apieron.
  - Library of Congress, 1924-1966; 8.1
    - General, 1940s-1980s (Box 13, Folder 3-6)
    - Abraham Lincoln, Portrait and Photographic Plates, 1950-1952 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Acquisition Policy, 1940-1950 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Administrative, 1947-1952 (Box 13, Folder 9-10)
    - The Albertype Company Collection, 1951-1953 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - American Documentation Institute, 1948-1951 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Architectural Photographs, Union Catalog, circa 1951 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Army Medical Library, circa 1950s (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Art Programs and Print Collections, 1946-1951 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Bennington College, 1950-1951 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Bibliographies of Iconographic Books, circa 1950 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Cartoons, Clippings from Multiple Sources, circa 1950s (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Cartoons, Mounted, circa 1949 (Box 13, Folder 19-20)
    - Cartoons from New Yorker Magazine, 1977-1987 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Cataloging, General Index, 1948-1952 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Cataloging Manuals, 1954 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Classification, circa 1937-1950 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Classification, Special Libraries Association, 1925-1939 (Box 13, Folder 25-26)
    - Classification, Spivack System, 1949-1954 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Conference, Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, 1951-1952 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Copying Camera, circa 1950 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Copyright Article, 1937-1952 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Copyright Office, 1949-1951 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Copyright of Photographs, 1953 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1944-1951 (Box 14, Folder 7-8)
    - Correspondence and Notes, 1947-1952 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - "Culture" as Arrangement in Art Reproduction Film, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Description of Collection of Notes, circa 1940s (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Directory of Iconographic Collections Outside Library of Congress, 1944-1948 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - The Dome, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Drafts for Manual, Unused, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Drafts and Notes on Matthew B. Brady, 1946-1954 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Draft of Proposal for Book on Library of Congress Collections, circa 1951 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Envelope Samples, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Equipment and Supplies, circa 1951 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Exhibitions, 1947-1952 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - File Methods for Photographic Bibliographies, circa 1950s (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Filmstrips, circa 1947 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Forgotten Photographers (1951) at Museum of Modern Art (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Forgotten Photographers (1951), Response and Developments (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - George Eastman House, circa 1950s (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - General Guide to Photographic Collections, 1943-1950 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Graphs as a Form, Sample, circa 1950s (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Guide to Materials Relating to Psychological Warfare, 1953 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Guide to Special Collections, Memos, 1952-1954 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Guide to Special Collections, Typescript, 1955 (Box 14, Folder 29-30)
    - History of Photography, Miscellaneous Notes, 1947-1953 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Huth, Hans, Union Catalog of Negatives, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - Iconography, 1945-1970s (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Iconography Activity in Art Museums, 1950-1952 (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - Iconography, "The American Indian and the West" (1947), Exhibition Catalog (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - Iconography, Miscellaneous Applications, 1948-1951 (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - Index to American Design, 1940-1943 (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Institute of Human Relations at Yale, 1945-1953 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - International Business Machines Corporation, 1949 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Johnston, Frances Benjamin, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Kennedy, Clarence, 1949 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Library Catalog, Inclusion of Photo Collection, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Life Magazine Exhibition Program, 1950-1952 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Lists of People to Contact, 1940s (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - A Machine Method for Scientific Literature Research by Delbert L. Ballard and Frederick G. Dhyse, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Microfilm, Photo Files to Card Forms, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Motion Pictures, 1950-1952 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Motion Picture Library, 1943 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Motion Picture Report, 1943-1945 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Naval Historical Foundation, 1947-1951 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Negative, Flow of Work Chart for Photographic Section, 1944 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Negative Jackets, 1945-1950 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Other Collections of Interest, 1924-1951 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Photographic Album Samples, circa 1950s (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Photograph Agencies, circa 1950s (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Photographic Applications, 1947-1960 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Photography Bibliography, circa 1950s (Box 15, Folder 20-29)
    - Photography Bibliography, circa 1950s (Box 16, Folder 1-3)
    - Photographers, Bibliography Cards, circa 1950s (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Photography Equipment, 1930s (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Photographic Prints, circa 1954 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Photographic Procedures, Daguerreotypes, circa 1950s (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Photograph Samples, Captioning Methods, 1941-1942 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Photographic Samples, Lamination, circa 1950s (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Photographic Planning Activities, 1944-1964 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Photographic Publications, 1963-1966 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Photo Lists for Book or Exhibit, circa 1950s (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Prices of Photographs, circa 1936 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Printed Material, 1932-1954 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Prints for Iconography Purchase, 1950 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Prints and Photographs Division Manual, 1945-1950 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Prokudin-Gorsky Collection, 1946-1951 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Punch Card Samples and Notes for Print Cataloging, circa 1950 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Raw Material for Article on Charles E. Norton, 1951 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Reference Guide, 1952 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Report on National Film Library, 1943 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Reproductions, New Techniques and Samples, circa 1940s (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Samples of Restrictions of Use on Photographs, 1940s (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Section of Library of Congress Quarterly Journal, 1953 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Seminars on American Culture in Cooperstown, New York, 1951-1952 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Sketch Draft of Book on Library of Congress Collections, circa 1951 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Sources of Reproductions, 1948-1949 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Specifications for Paper, 1947-1951 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Symposium and Correspondence with Life Magazine, 1950-1952 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Technical Practices and Equipment, 1942-1954 (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - UNESCO, 1946-1947 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - University of California Proposed Photograph Collection, circa 1950s (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - Vanderbilt's Activities in Washington D.C., 1951-1954 (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - Vanderbilt's Other Activities While at Library of Congress, circa 1950s (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Graphic History Society, 1945-1976; 8.2
    - General, 1953-1968 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Abstracting, 1951-1954 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Annual Meeting, 1954 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Applications of Iconography, 1951-1955 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Bibliography of Picture Books, circa 1953 (Box 17, Folder 5-7)
    - Bibliography of Iconographic Books, circa 1953 (Box 17, Folder 8-13)
    - Bibliography of Iconographic Books from Library of Congress Proofsheets, circa 1953 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Booklets, 1948-1952 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Booklets, 1953 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Catalogs of Available Public Relations Pictures, 1953-1954 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Committee on Contemporary Photography, 1953-1954 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Committee on Iconography in the Fine Arts, 1953-1955 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Copyright Registration Certificates, 1953-1954 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence (Box 18)
      - A, 1952-1957 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - B, 1952-1957 (Box 18, Folder 6-7)
      - C, 1952-1957 (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Comite International des Sciences Historiques and Commission d'Iconographie, 1950-1954 (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - D, 1952-1955 (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - E-G, 1952-1957 (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - H, 1952-1957 (Box 18, Folder 12)